原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     盐湖水蒸气   IronDerby   SophiaSaaaga
翻译     杏仁斯嘉丽   木浅Nox   无限草
校对     复仇草
时间轴     想念Gallifrey的Wholock   西查
这里是阿斯加德难民船  要员号
This is the Asgardian refugee vessel Statesman.
后期     8T
总监     somehacker   草草
我们遭遇了袭击
We are under assault.
我重复  我们遭遇了袭击
I repeat, we are under assault.
引擎熄火  生命保障系统濒临崩溃
The engines are dead, life support failing.
请求附近飞船支援
Requesting aid from any vessel within range.
我们距阿斯加德22个跳跃点
We are 22 jump points out of Asgard.
船上人员均是阿斯加德家庭
Our crew is made up of Asgardian families.
这里的士兵很少
We have very few soldiers here.
这并非战舰
This is not a warcraft.
我重复  这并非战舰
I repeat, this is not a warcraft.
听我说  你们应当开心
Hear me and rejoice.
你们有幸
You have had the privilege
被伟大泰坦所拯救
of being saved by the Great Titan.
你们或许觉得这是苦难
You may think this is suffering.
不是的
No.
这是拯救
It is salvation.
因为你们的牺牲
Universal scales tip toward balance
宇宙的天平又平衡了一些
because of your sacrifice.
笑笑吧
Smile.
即便是死了
For even in death,
你们也成为了灭霸的孩子
you have become Children of Thanos.
我懂得失败的感觉
I know what it's like to lose.
明明深切地知道你是对的
To feel so desperately that you're right...
却还是失败了
yet to fail, nonetheless.
是很可怕
It's frightening.
让人的腿发软
Turns the legs to jelly.
但我问你  这又何必
But I ask you, to what end?
害怕  逃避
Dread it, run from it...
命运总会到来
destiny arrives all the same.
现在  它来了
And now, it's here.
或者我该说
Or should I say...
我来了
I am.
你话太多了
You talk too much.
宇宙魔方
The Tesseract.
换你哥哥的脑袋
Or your brother's head.
你应该有所取舍吧
I assume you have a preference.
当然
Oh, I do.
杀了他吧
Kill away.
好吧  住手
All right, stop!
宇宙魔方不在我们这儿
We don't have the Tesseract.
它在阿斯加德上被毁了
It was destroyed on Asgard.
你真是最差劲的弟弟
You really are the worst brother.
我向你保证  哥哥
I assure you, brother...
我们还会时来运转的
the sun will shine on us again.
你的乐观用错了地方  阿斯加德人
Your optimism is misplaced, Asgardian.
首先  我不是阿斯加德人
Well, for one thing, I'm not Asgardian.
另外
And for another...
我们有绿巨人
we have a Hulk.
让他玩吧
Let him have his fun.
众神之父
Allfathers...
让黑暗魔法最后一次
let the dark magic flow through me one last...
流过我
time.
那是个错误
That was a mistake.
不
No!
我会要你偿命的
You're going to die for that.
卑微的我
My humble personage...
向您的伟大臣服
bows before your grandeur.
从没有过什么人  如此强大
No other being has ever had the might...
如此崇高
nay, the nobility...
能够操控不仅一枚  而是两枚无限宝石的力量
to wield not one, but two Infinity Stones.
宇宙已经唾手可得
The universe lies within your grasp.
地球上还有两颗
There are two more stones on Earth.
找到它们  我的孩子  带去泰坦星上给我
Find them, my children, and bring them to me on Titan.
父亲  我们不会辜负你的
Father, we will not fail you.
容我插嘴
If I might interject.
如果你们要去地球  你们或许需要向导
If you're going to Earth, you might want a guide.
我在这方面还有点经验
I do have a bit of experience in that arena.
如果你认为失败也算经验的话
If you consider failure experience.
我认为经验就是经验
I consider experience experience.
全能的灭霸
Almighty Thanos...
我  洛基  阿斯加德王子
I, Loki, prince of Asgard...
奥丁森
Odinson...
约顿海姆的合法国王
the rightful king of Jotunheim...
恶作剧之神
god of mischief...
在此向你宣誓
do hereby pledge to you...
不死的忠诚
my undying fidelity.
不死
Undying?
你措辞该更小心点的
You should choose your words more carefully.
你
You...
永远不会成为
will never be...
神
a god.
不
No!
这次别想复活了
No resurrections this time.
不  洛基
No. Loki.
你真的一点钱都没有吗
Seriously, you don't have any money?
对物质的依恋  就是与精神的断层
Attachment to the material is detachment from the spiritual.
我会把这话告诉熟食店的人的
I'll tell the guys at the deli.
或许他们能给你做个形而上的黑面包火腿三明治
Maybe they'll make you a metaphysical ham on rye.
等等  我好像有两百
Wait, wait, wait. I think I have 200.
美元吗
Dollars?
-卢比  -那是多少
- Rupees. - Which is?
1.5美元
Buck and a half.
你想要什么
What do you want?
金枪鱼三明治倒是不错
I wouldn't say no to a tuna melt.
灭霸要来了
Thanos is coming.
他要来了
He's coming.
谁
Who?
复仇者联盟3：无限战争
慢点  慢点
Slow down, slow down.
-我解释给你听  -你在说胡话呢
- I'll spell it out for you. - You're totally rambling.
-没有啦  -我没听懂
- No, I'm not. - You lost me.
你知道那种  做梦的时候
Look, you know how you're having a dream,
觉得要上厕所的感觉吧
and in the dream you gotta pee.
-嗯  -好
- Yeah. - Okay.
然后你会发现  "天呐
And then you're like, "Oh, my God.
怎么到处都没厕所  怎么办啊
"There's no bathrooms. What am I gonna do?
-有人在看啊"  -是啊
- "Oh, someone's watching." - Right.
-"我要尿裤子了"  -然后你醒过来
- "Oh, I'm gonna go in my pants." - And then you wake up
发现你其实是真想尿尿
and in real life you actually have to pee.
-没错  -嗯
- Yes. - Yeah.
-好  -每个人都做这种梦
- Okay. - Everybody has that.
是啊  这就是我想说的
Right, that's the point I'm trying to make.
关于这一点  昨晚  我梦到我们生了个孩子
Apropos of that, last night I dreamt we had a kid.
感觉可真了
It was so real.
我们还以一个奇怪的叔叔给他起了名
We named him after your eccentric uncle.
他叫什么来着
Uh, what was his name?
-哦  -摩根  摩根
- Right. - Morgan! Morgan.
-于是你醒来  -当然了
- So you woke up... - Naturally.
觉得我们...
...and thought that we were...
-要有了  -嗯
- Expecting. - Yeah.
-有吗  -没有
- Yes? - No.
我梦到了  可真了
I had a dream about it. It was so real.
如果你想要孩子
If you wanted to have a kid...
你就不会这么做了
you wouldn't have done that.
我很高兴你提到了这个  因为这没什么
I'm glad you brought this up, 'cause it's nothing.
就是纳米粒子的储存器
It's just a housing unit for nanoparticles.
这话是帮倒忙
You're not helping your case, okay?
不  这是能拆掉的
No, this is detachable. It's not a...
你不需要它
You don't need that.
我知道  我做了手术
I know, I had the surgery.
我就是想保护我们
I'm just trying to protect us...
还有未来更多的我们什么的
and future usses and that's it.
以防衣橱里藏了怪物
Just in case there's a monster in the closet.
-而不是  -衬衫
- Instead of, you know... - Shirts.
你好了解我
You know me so well.
-天呐  -你还能接我的话
- God. - You finish all my sentences.
你的衣橱里该放衬衣
You should have shirts in your closet.
是啊
Yeah.
知道该有什么吗  再不制造意外了
You know what there should be? No more surprises.
我们今晚好好吃顿晚饭
We're gonna have a nice dinner tonight.
炫耀下这枚海瑞温斯顿的钻戒
Show off this Harry Winston.
是吧  今后再不制造什么意外了
Right? And we should have no more surprises. Ever.
我要向你保证
I should promise you.
-好  -真的
- Yes. - I will.
谢谢
Thank you.
托尼·斯塔克
Tony Stark.
我是斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇博士  我需要你跟我来
I'm Doctor Stephen Strange. I need you to come with me.
恭喜你们要结婚了
Oh, uh, congratulations on the wedding, by the way.
抱歉  你是卖票的吗
I'm sorry, you giving out tickets to something?
我们需要你帮忙
We need your help.
可以不夸张地说
It's not overselling it to say that
这事关全宇宙的命运
the fate of the universe is at stake.
"我们"是谁
And who's "we"?
托尼
Hey, Tony.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
派珀
Pepper.
你没事吧
You okay?
宇宙之初
At the dawn of the universe,
是一片虚无  然后...
there was nothing. Then...
大爆炸把六颗元素水晶
The Big Bang sent six elemental crystals...
抛到了新宇宙的深处
hurtling across the virgin universe.
这些无限宝石
These Infinity Stones
每一颗都控制一种存在的基本方面
each control an essential aspect of existence.
空间
Space.
现实
Reality.
力量
Power.
灵魂
Soul.
心灵
Mind.
还有时间
And Time.
再跟我说一遍他的名字
Tell me his name again.
灭霸
Thanos.
他就像瘟疫  托尼
He's a plague, Tony.
他入侵星球  肆意夺取
He invades planets. He takes what he wants.
抹去半数人口
He wipes out half the population.
当初是他派洛基来的
He sent Loki.
纽约的袭击  是他搞的鬼
The attack on New York, that's him.
决战来了
This is it.
我们还有多少时间
What's our timeline?
不知道  他拿到了力量和空间宝石
No telling. He has the Power and Space Stones.
这已经使他成为全宇宙最有威力的人了
That already makes him the strongest creature in the whole universe.
如果他拿到全部六颗宝石  托尼
If he gets his hands on all six stones, Tony...
他能以此前无法想象的方式毁灭生命
He could destroy life on a scale hitherto undreamt of.
你刚刚真的说了"此前无法想象"吗
Did you seriously just say "hitherto undreamt of"?
你真的要倚在宇宙大锅上吗
Are you seriously leaning on the Cauldron of the Cosmos?
是叫这个吗
Is that what it is?
我就不跟你计较了
I'm going to allow that.
如果灭霸需要全部六颗
If Thanos needs all six,
那我们何不毁了这颗
why don't we just stick this one down a garbage disposal?
不行
No can do.
我们曾起誓要以性命维护时间宝石
We swore an oath to protect the Time Stone with our lives.
我还曾起誓要戒掉乳制品
And I swore off dairy...
但班杰瑞以我命名了一种冰淇淋口味
but then Ben & Jerry's named a flavor after me.
-斯塔克狂热榛仁  -不赖啊
- Stark Raving Hazelnuts. - Not bad.
有点牙碜
A bit chalky.
我最喜欢大块绿巨人热巧克力
A Hunk of Hulk of Burning Fudge is our favorite.
-有这玩意吗  -不重要
- That's a thing? - Whatever.
重点是  情况会变
Point is, things change.
我们保护时间宝石的誓言不能改变
Our oath to protect the Time Stone cannot change.
这颗宝石可能是我们对抗灭霸的最佳机会了
And this stone may be the best chance we have against Thanos.
那么反过来
Yeah, so conversely,
也可能是他对付我们的最佳机会
it may also be his best chance against us.
如果我们不能尽职的话
Well, if we don't do our jobs.
你的职责究竟是什么
What is your job exactly?
除了捏气球动物
Besides making balloon animals.
保护你的现实  混球
Protecting your reality, douchebag.
好了  各位  我们能先别吵吗
Okay, guys. Could we table this discussion right now?
事实就是  我们有这颗宝石
The fact is we have this stone.
我们知道它在哪
We know where it is.
幻视还带着心灵宝石不知道人在何处呢
Vision is out there somewhere with the Mind Stone...
我们得马上找到他
and we have to find him now.
问题就在这里
Yeah, that's the thing.
什么意思
What do you mean?
两周前  幻视关闭了他的应答机
Two weeks ago, Vision turned off his transponder.
他下线了
He's offline.
-什么  -嗯
- What? - Yeah.
托尼  你又弄丢一个超级机器人
Tony, you lost another super-bot?
我没弄丢他  他没那么简单了  他在进化
I didn't lose him. He's more than that. He's evolving.
那谁能找到幻视
Who could find Vision then?
该死
Shit.
史蒂夫·罗杰斯或许能
Probably Steve Rogers.
太好了
Oh, great.
或许吧
Maybe.
但是
But...
打给他
Call him.
没那么简单
It's not that easy.
天呐  我们真是好久没联络了  是吧
God, we haven't caught up in a spell, have we?
是啊
No.
复仇者联盟解散了  我们完了
The Avengers broke up. We're toast.
解散了
Broke up?
像乐队那样吗  像披头士那样吗
Like a band? Like... Like the Beatles?
队长和我闹得很僵
Cap and I fell out hard.
我们现在不说话了
We're not on speaking terms.
托尼  听我说
Tony, listen to me.
托尔死了
Thor's gone.
灭霸要来了
Thanos is coming.
你跟不跟谁说话都无所谓了
It doesn't matter who you're talking to or not.
翻盖手机
Flip phone.
史蒂夫·罗杰斯
博士  你是在自己动头发吗
Say, Doc, you wouldn't happen to be moving your hair, would ya?
现在没有
Not at the moment, no.
你没事吧
You okay?
-帮帮他  -班纳
- Help him! - Banner!
-王  精神点  -去吧  我们能行
- Wong! Look alive! - Go, go! We got it!
星期五  什么情况
Friday, what am I looking at?
不确定  我还在查看
Not sure. I'm working on it.
你最好把时间宝石
You might wanna put that Time Stone
塞后兜里  博士
in your back pocket, Doc!
还是用它更好
Might wanna use it.
内德  我需要你分散大家的注意
Ned, hey. I need you to cause a distraction.
我去
Holy shit.
我们都要死了
We're all gonna die!
那里有架飞船
There's a spaceship!
-怎么回事啊  -天呐
- What's going on? - Oh, my God!
你们这些孩子怎么回事
What's the matter with you kids?
没见过宇宙飞船啊
You never seen a spaceship before?
星期五  疏散43街以南的群众
Friday, evac anyone south of 43rd Street.
通知应急人员
Notify first responders.
好
Will do.
听我说  你们应当开心
Hear me and rejoice.
你们即将死在
You are about to die
灭霸的孩子手下
at the hands of the Children of Thanos.
心怀感激吧
Be thankful...
你们毫无意义的人生将贡献...
that your meaningless lives are now contributing...
抱歉  地球今天歇业
I'm sorry, Earth is closed today.
你们最好收拾东西滚蛋
You better pack it up and get outta here.
宝石守护者
Stonekeeper.
这喋喋不休的动物能替你说话吗
Does this chattering animal speak for you?
当然不  我想说什么自己说
Certainly not. I speak for myself.
你们在这座城市和这颗星球都不受欢迎
You're trespassing in this city and on this planet.
就是滚蛋的意思  章鱼哥
He means get lost, Squidward.
他让我厌烦
He exhausts me.
把宝石拿来给我
Bring me the stone.
班纳  你想出手吗
Banner, you want a piece?
并不想
No, not really.
但我什么时候如愿过了
But when do I ever get what I want?
这就对了
That's right.
好  加把劲
Okay. Push!
好久没见了
It's been a while.
能再见到你会很高兴的  哥们
It's gonna be good to have you, buddy.
好吧
Okay.
容我...我得集中精神
Let me just... I need to concentrate here for a second.
来啊  拜托
Come on, come on, man.
天呐
God!
那家伙呢
Where's your guy?
我不知道  我们最近有点问题
I don't know. We've sorta been having a thing.
-现在不是有问题的时候  -我知道
- It's no time for a thing. - I know.
那才是问题  来吧
That's the thing right there. Let's go.
哥们  你让我在巫师面前下不来台了
Dude, you're embarrassing me in front of the wizards.
托尼  抱歉  不是我不能  就是他不想
Tony, I'm sorry. Either I can't or he won't.
没事的
It's okay.
退后吧  替我看着点他  谢谢
Hey, stand down. Keep an eye on him. Thank you.
-交给我吧  -该死
- I have him. - Damn it.
那是哪来的
Where'd that come from?
是纳米科技
It's nanotech.
喜欢吗  是我...
You like it? A little something I...
班纳博士  如果你的绿朋友不打算来了
Doctor Banner, if the rest of your green friend won't be joining us...
快把宝石送走
Gotta get that stone outta here, now.
我人在宝石在
It stays with me.
没错  再见
Exactly. Bye.
托尼  你没事吧
Tony, you okay?
-情况怎么样  是好是坏  -可好了
- How we doing? Good? Bad? - Really, really good.
可好了  你想不想帮忙啊
Really good. Do you plan on helping out?
我也想  他不肯出来
I'm trying. He won't come out.
锤子
Hammer.
拜托  绿巨人  你这是干什么啊
Come on, Hulk! What are you doing to me?
出来啊  出来啊
Come out! Come out! Come out!
不要
No!
什么叫"不要"
What do you mean, "No"?
好啊  斯塔克先生  你好吗
Hey, man. What's up, Mr. Stark?
孩子  你哪冒出来的
Kid, where'd you come from?
学校组织去现代艺术博物馆
A field trip to MoMA.
这家伙什么毛病  斯塔克先生
What is this guy's problem, Mr. Stark?
他是外太空来的
Uh, he's from space.
他是来偷一个巫师的项链的
He came here to steal a necklace from a wizard.
你的能力很有意思
Your powers are quaint.
你一定很受孩子的喜欢吧
You must be popular with children.
虽然是简单的咒语  但不可攻破
It's a simple spell but quite unbreakable.
那我就先杀了你再拿
Then I'll take it off your corpse.
你会发现
You'll find
想解除
removing
一个死人的咒语
a dead man's spell
会很困难
troublesome.
你会生不如死
You'll only wish you were dead.
不
No!
孩子  就是那个巫师  快去
Kid, that's the wizard. Get on it.
去了
On it!
好过分
Not cool.
抓到你了
Gotcha!
等等
Wait!
斯塔克先生  我被光吸上去了
Uh, Mr. Stark, I'm being beamed up.
撑着  孩子
Hang on, kid.
王  我婚礼你一定要来
Wong, you're invited to my wedding.
给我点动力  星期五
Give me a little juice, Friday.
启动17A
Unlock 17:A.
彼得  放手吧  我来接住你
Pete, you gotta let go. I'm gonna catch you.
但你叫我救巫师的
But you said save the wizard!
我不能呼吸了
I can't breathe.
我们太高了  你要没空气了
We're too high up. You're running out of air.
是啊  这讲得通
Yeah. That makes sense.
斯塔克先生  这里面闻起来像新车
Mr. Stark, it smells like a new car in here!
一路顺风  孩子
Happy trails, kid.
-星期五  送他回家  -好
- Friday, send him home. - Yep.
拜托
Oh, come on!
老板  波茨小姐来电
Boss, incoming call from Miss Potts.
托尼  天呐
Tony? Oh, my God.
你没事吧  怎么回事啊
Are you all right? What's going on?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
但我们8:30的预约可能得延期了
I just think we might have to push our 8:30 res.
为什么
Why?
就是我可能一时半会儿回不去
Just 'cause I'll probably not make it back for a while.
告诉我你没在那艘飞船上
Tell me you're not on that ship.
嗯
Yeah.
天呐  不  告诉我你没在那艘飞船上
God, no, please tell me you're not on the ship.
亲爱的  对不起
Honey, I'm sorry.
对不起  我不知道该怎么说
I'm sorry, I don't know what to say.
给我回来  托尼  我发誓
Come back here, Tony. I swear to God.
-派珀  -赶紧给我回来
- Pep. - Come back here right now.
回来
Come back.
老板  信号要断了
Boss, we're losing her.
我也去
I'm going too.
天呐
Oh, my God!
我就该待在校车上
I shoulda stayed on the bus.
你去哪
Where you going?
时间宝石被夺走了
The Time Stone's been taken.
圣殿无人守护
The Sanctum remains unguarded.
你要怎么办
What will you do?
我要打个电话
I'm gonna make a call.
史蒂夫·罗杰斯
外  太  空
BGM: Rubberband Man  By  The Spinners
唱吧  德拉克斯
Sing it, Drax!
我们为什么要这么做来着
Why are we doing this again?
有人发了求救信号  火箭
It's a distress signal, Rocket.
可能有人有危险
Someone could be dying.
这我懂  但我们为什么要来
I get that, but why are we doing it?
因为我们是好人
'Cause we're nice.
或许求救的人
And maybe whoever it is
会给我们点切达奶酪作为感谢
will give us a little cheddar cheese for our effort.
-这不是重点  -这不是重点
- Which isn't the point. - Which isn't the point.
如果他不给谢礼
I mean, if he doesn't pony up...
我们就夺他的船
We take his ship.
-没错  -正确
- Exactly! - Bingo!
好嘞
All right!
我们要到了
We are arriving.
好了  护卫队
All right, Guardians,
别忘了  情况可能很危险
don't forget this might be dangerous...
大家都凶起来
so let's put on our mean faces.
防卫者
格鲁特  马上把那玩意放起来
Groot, put that thing away, now.
别让我再说你
I don't wanna tell you again.
格鲁特
Groot.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot!
怎么说话呢
Language!
你胆子不小  小子
You got some acorns on you, kid.
自从你开始分泌树液
Ever since you got a little sap,
你就变成了个小混蛋
you're a total d-hole.
再这么下去  我就把那玩意给砸了
Now, keep it up, and I'm gonna smash that thing to pieces.
发生了什么
What happened?
天呐
Oh, my God.
看来我们别想拿钱了
Looks like we're not getting paid.
开雨刷  开雨刷
Wipers! Wipers!
把它弄掉
Get it off.
这哥们怎么会还活着
How the hell is this dude still alive?
他不是个"哥们"
He is not a dude.
你是个哥们
You're a dude.
这  是个男人
This... This is a man.
一个帅气的肌肉男
A handsome, muscular man.
我也挺肌肉的
I'm muscular.
你骗谁呢  奎尔
But who are you kidding, Quill?
你再吃一个三明治就是一身肥膘了
You're one sandwich away from fat.
得了吧
Yeah, right.
没错  奎尔  你是胖了点
It's true, Quill. You have put on weight.
什么
What?
卡魔拉  你也觉得我...
Gamora, do you think I'm...
他很焦虑  愤怒
He is anxious, angry.
他失去了很多  非常愧疚
He feels tremendous loss and guilt.
简直就像一个海盗跟一个天使生了个孩子
It's like a pirate had a baby with an angel.
这对我真是一记警钟啊  好吧
This is a real wake-up call for me. Okay.
我去买个博飞健身器  认真减肥
I'm gonna get a Bowflex. I'm gonna commit.
再去弄个哑铃
I'm gonna get some dumbbells.
你知道哑铃是不能吃的吧
You know you can't eat dumbbells, right?
他的肌肉就像是柯塔蒂金属纤维做的
It's like his muscles are made of Cotati metal fibers.
别给他的肌肉按摩了
Stop massaging his muscles.
弄醒他
Wake him up.
醒来
Wake.
你们是谁
Who the hell are you guys?
自从我认识灭霸  他就只有一个目标
The entire time I knew Thanos, he only ever had one goal.
让宇宙获得平衡
To bring balance to the universe
方法是抹去一半生命
by wiping out half of all life.
他以前会一个个星球地杀人
He used to kill people planet by planet,
一次次地进行屠杀
massacre by massacre.
包括我的星球
Including my own.
如果他拿到全部六颗无限宝石
If he gets all six Infinity Stones...
那他打一个响指就能实现愿望
he can do it with the snap of his fingers like this.
你似乎对灭霸很了解
You seem to know a great deal about Thanos.
卡魔拉是灭霸的女儿
Gamora is the daughter of Thanos.
你父亲杀了我弟弟
Your father killed my brother.
天呐
Oh, boy.
严格讲是继父
Stepfather, technically.
她跟你一样恨他
And she hates him as much as you do.
家家有本难念的经
Families can be tough.
我父亲死前
Before my father died,
才跟我说我还有个异母姐姐
he told me that I had a half-sister...
被他囚禁在了地狱
that he imprisoned in Hel.
然后她回了家  捅瞎了我的眼睛
And then she returned home and stabbed me in the eye.
于是我不得不杀了她
So I had to kill her.
人生啊  是吧
That's life though, isn't it, I guess.
兜兜转转
Goes round and round and...
我能理解你的痛苦
I feel your pain.
我也能理解你的痛苦
I feel your pain as well, because...
虽然这不是比赛
I mean, it's not a competition,
但我也吃过不少苦
but I've been through a lot.
我爸杀了我妈
My father killed my mother.
然后我不得不杀了我爸
And then I had to kill my father.
那可痛苦了
That was hard.
可能比杀姐姐还痛苦
Probably even harder than having to kill a sister.
而且我还两眼完好无损地回来了
Plus, I came out with both my eyes, which was...
我需要一把锤子  不是勺子
I need a hammer, not a spoon.
这玩意怎么开  有什么...
How do I open this thing? Is there some sort of, uh...
四位密码  是生日吗
A four-digit code, maybe? Maybe a birthdate.
-你干什么呢  -开走你们的飞行舱
- What are you doing? - Taking your pod.
你别想
No, you're not.
你今天别想开走我们的飞行舱  先生
You will not be taking our pod today, sir.
奎尔  你是在故意把嗓音压低吗
Quill, are you making your voice deeper?
-没有  -就有
- No. - You are.
你在模仿那个男神  好奇怪
You're imitating the god-man. It's weird.
我没有
No, I'm not.
-他又来了  -我的嗓音就是这样
- He just did it again! - This is my voice.
你在嘲笑我吗
Are you mocking me?
-你在嘲笑我吗  -别闹了  你又那样了
- Are you mocking me? - Stop it. You did it again.
他想模仿我
He's trying to copy me.
你给我停下
I need you to stop doing that.
-够了  -他先开始的
- Enough! - He's doing it first.
我们得阻止灭霸
We need to stop Thanos.
所以  我们得查明
Which means we need to find out
他接下来要去哪
where he's going next.
虚无知地[不去哪]
Knowhere.
他肯定会去什么地方的
He must be going somewhere.
不对  虚无知地吗
No, no. Knowhere?
那是个地方  我们去过  烂爆了
It's a place. We've been there. It sucks.
-抱歉  那是我们的食物  -现在不是了
- Excuse me, that's our food. - Not anymore.
托尔  他为什么要去虚无知地
Thor, why would he go to Knowhere?
因为多年来
Because for years...
现实宝石一直安全地放在那里
the Reality Stone's been safely stored there
在一个叫收藏者的人手上
with a man called the Collector.
如果是在收藏者手上  那就不安全了
If it's with the Collector, then it's not safe.
只有白痴才会把宝石交给那人
Only an idiot would give that man a stone.
-或是天才  -你怎么知道
- Or a genius. - How do you know...
他不会去找其他的宝石
he's not going for one of the other stones?
一共有六颗宝石
There are six stones out there.
灭霸已经拿到了力量宝石
Thanos already has the Power Stone...
那是他上周摧毁山达尔星时偷走的
because he stole it last week when he decimated Xandar.
他从我这儿偷走了空间宝石
He stole the Space Stone from me...
还摧毁了我的飞船  杀了我一半人民
when he destroyed my ship and slaughtered half my people.
时间和心灵宝石在地球上很安全
The Time and Mind Stones are safe on Earth.
在复仇者联盟手里
They're with the Avengers.
-复仇者联盟  -地球最强大的英雄
- The Avengers? - Earth's mightiest heroes.
就像凯文·贝肯吗
Like Kevin Bacon?
或许有他吧  我不知道
He may be on the team. I don't know.
我挺久没回去了
I haven't been there in a while.
至于灵魂宝石  根本没人见过
As for the Soul Stone, well, no one's ever seen that.
都没人知道它在哪
No one even knows where it is.
因此灭霸得不到它
Therefore Thanos can't get it.
因此他会去虚无知地
Therefore he's going to Knowhere.
好拿到现实宝石
Hence he'll be getting the Reality Stone.
不客气
You're welcome.
那我们得马上去虚无知地
Then we have to go to Knowhere now.
不  我们得去尼德威阿尔
Wrong. Where we have to go is Nidavellir.
-那个词是编出来的  -所有词都是编出来的
- That's a made-up word. - All words are made up.
尼德威阿尔是真的  你认真的吗
Nidavellir is real? Seriously?
那地方是个传奇
That place is a legend.
他们能造出最强大  最可怕的武器
They make the most powerful, horrific weapons
来折腾整个宇宙
to ever torment the universe.
我可是非常愿意去的
I would very much like to go there, please.
这只兔子说的对
The rabbit is correct
它显然是你们当中最聪明的
and clearly the smartest among you.
-兔子  -只有矮人伊特里能造出我需要的武器
- Rabbit?  - Only Eitri the Dwarf can make me the weapon I need.
你就是船长吧  先生
I assume you're the captain, sir.
有眼光
You're very perceptive.
你看起来像个高贵的领袖
You seem like a noble leader.
你愿意跟我一起去尼德威阿尔吗
Will you join me on my quest to Nidavellir?
让我问下船长  等一下  我就是船长
Let me just ask the captain. Oh, wait a second, it's me!
-好  我加入  -太棒了
- Yeah. I'll go. - Wonderful!
不过  我才是船长
Except for that I'm the captain.
安静
Quiet.
-那是我的背包  -坐下吧你
- That's my backpack. - Go sit down.
这是我的飞船
Look, this is my ship.
我才不会去什么...
And I'm not goin' to...
等一下  那是什么样的武器
Wait, what kinda weapon are we talkin' about here?
能杀灭霸的那种
The Thanos-killing kind.
你不觉得我们每个人都应该弄把那样的武器吗
Don't you think that we should all have a weapon like that?
不  你们没有驾驭它们的力量
No. You simply lack the strength to wield them.
你们的身体会碎裂
Your bodies would crumble
思维会崩溃  甚至疯掉
as your minds collapsed into madness.
我现在更想要了  会不会很奇怪
Is it weird that I wanna do it even more now?
没错  是有一点
Mmm, a little bit, yeah.
如果我们不去虚无知地
If we don't go to Knowhere
而灭霸又得到一颗宝石
and Thanos retrieves another stone...
他就会强大得不可阻挡了
he'll be too powerful to stop.
-他已经不可阻挡了  -我有办法了
- He already is. - I got it figured out.
我们有两艘船
We got two ships
和一群各种各样的白痴
and a large assortment of morons.
我和格鲁特跟这位海盗天使走
So me and Groot will go with the pirate angel here.
白痴们去虚无知地
And the morons will go to Knowhere
试图阻止灭霸
to try to stop Thanos.
-好吗  好  -很好
- Cool? Cool. - So cool.
就说一句
For the record...
我知道你跟他走
I know that you're going with him
是因为灭霸不在那里
because it's where Thanos isn't.
你真的不应该
You know, you really shouldn't
这样跟你的船长讲话  奎尔
talk that way to your captain, Quill.
走了  格鲁特
Come on, Groot.
把游戏放下  你的脑子会烂掉的
Put that game down. You'll rot your brain.
再会了  祝你们好运  白痴们
I bid you farewell and good luck, morons.
再见
Bye.
小幻
Vis?
又是宝石
Is it the stone again?
它好像在跟我说话
It's as if it's speaking to me.
它说什么
What does it say?
我...不知道  但它说了些什么
I don't... I don't know, but something.
告诉我你感觉到了什么
Tell me what you feel.
我只感觉到了你
I just feel you.
苏  格  兰
10点有一班去格拉斯哥的列车
So there's a 10:00 A.M. to Glasgow...
这样你回去之前  我们还能一起多待会儿
which would give us more time together before you went back.
如果我错过那班车呢
What if I miss that train?
11点还有一班
There's an 11:00.
如果我错过所有车次呢
What if I missed all the trains?
这次我不回去了怎么样
What if this time I didn't go back?
但你向斯塔克承诺过
But you gave Stark your word.
我更想向你许下承诺
I'd rather give it to you.
也有人在等我回去
Well, there are people who are expecting me too, you know.
我们都做过承诺
We both made promises.
但没对彼此承诺过
Not to each other.
旺达
Wanda.
两年了  我们偷来了这些相处的时光
For two years, we've stolen these moments...
想看看我们是不是合得来
trying to see if this could work and...
我不知道
I don't know.
我只想说说自己的看法
You know what, I'm just gonna speak for myself.
我觉得...
I think...
-我们合得来  -是啊
- It works. - It works.
是啊
It works.
留下来
Stay.
留下陪我
Stay with me.
或者算了  如果我出格了
Or not. If I'm overstepping...
纽约遭袭击
他们是什么
What are they?
正是宝石警告我的东西
What the stone was warning me about.
托尼·斯塔克失踪
我得走了
I have to go.
不  幻视
No, Vision.
幻视  如果那是真的
Vision, if that's true,
那也许回去不是最好的选择
then maybe going isn't the best idea.
旺达  我...
Wanda, I...
幻视
Vision!
那刀刃  让我无法变相
The blade, it stopped me from phasing.
-那可能吗  -不该这样的
- Is that even possible? - It isn't supposed to be.
我的系统正在崩溃
My systems are failing.
我开始觉得我们不该下床了
I'm beginning to think we should have stayed in bed.
小幻
Vis!
放弃宝石  她才能活
Give up the stone, and she lives.
放开他
Hands off.
快  快
Come on. Come on.
快  你得站起来
Come on, you gotta get up.
你得站起来  快
You gotta get up. Come on.
我们得走了
We have to go.
拜托  你走吧
Please. Please leave.
你让我留下来的
You asked me to stay.
-我要留下  -拜托
- I'm staying. - Please.
-起来  -我起不来
- Get up. - I can't.
我们不想杀你  但我们不会手软的
We don't wanna kill you, but we will.
过时不候
You'll never get the chance again.
你能站起来吗
Can you stand?
谢谢你  队长
Thank you, Captain.
先扶你上飞机吧
Let's get you on the jet.
我们不是说好了吗
Now, I thought we had a deal.
别走太远  保持联系  不要冒险
Stay close, check in, don't take any chances.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们只是需要时间
We just wanted time.
去哪里  队长
Where to, Cap?
回家
Home.
我们会安全的  会安全的
We'll be safe. We'll be safe.
泽霍贝瑞人
Zehobereians.
母亲  我母亲呢
Mother! Where's my mother?
不选一边就要死
Choose a side or die.
母亲
Mother!
一边是启示
One side is a revelation...
另一边是只有少数人拥有的荣耀
the other an honor known only to a few.
你怎么了  小家伙
What's wrong, little one?
我母亲  我母亲在哪
My mother. Where is my mother?
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我叫卡魔拉
Gamora.
你很有斗志  卡魔拉
You're quite the fighter, Gamora.
来
Come.
我来帮你
Let me help you.
你看
Look.
很漂亮是吧
Pretty, isn't it?
平衡感恰到好处  正是一切事物应有的样子
Perfectly balanced, as all things should be.
左右偏移太多的话...
Too much to one side or the other...
给  你试试
Here. You try.
安详地去见你们的造物主吧
Now, go in peace to meet your maker.
集中注意力
Concentrate.
这就对了  你掌握了
There. You've got it.
卡魔拉
Gamora.
你知不知道这些手榴弹
Do you know if these grenades
是炸掉蛋蛋的  还是毒气弹
are the blow-off-your-junk kind or the gas kind?
因为我想
Because I was thinking about
在皮带上挂几个
hanging a couple on my belt right here.
但我可不想被炸...
But I don't want to if they're the...
我需要你帮忙
I need to ask a favor.
当然
Yeah, sure.
不管怎样
One way or another,
我们都会与灭霸交手的
the path that we're on leads to Thanos.
这就是手榴弹的用处
Which is what the grenades are for.
抱歉  你要我帮什么忙
I'm sorry. What's the favor?
如果事情出了岔子
If things go wrong...
如果灭霸抓到了我
If Thanos gets me...
我要你答应我
I want you to promise me...
你会杀了我
you'll kill me.
什么
What?
我知道一些他不知道的事
I know something he doesn't.
如果他知道了
And if he finds it out,
那整个宇宙都有危险了
the entire universe could be at risk.
你知道什么
What do you know?
如果我告诉你  你也知道了
If I tell you, you'd know too.
如果这事如此重要
If it's so important...
难道我不该知道吗
shouldn't I?
除非你想死
Only if you wanna die.
为什么总有人要死
Why does somebody always have to die in this scenario?
你就
Just...
相信我  可能还要杀了我
Trust me. And possibly kill me.
我倒是愿意
I mean, I'd like to.
真的  但是你...
I really would. But you...
向我发誓
Swear to me.
以你母亲的名义向我发誓
Swear to me on your mother.
好
Okay.
好吧
老兄
Dude.
你在那里站了多久
How long have you been standing there?
一小时
An hour.
An hour?
你不是吧
Are you serious?
我已经掌握了
I've mastered the ability
纹丝不动站立的能力
of standing so incredibly still...
肉眼是看不到我的
that I become invisible to the eye.
看好了
Watch.
你在吃花生糖呢
You're eating a zarg-nut.
但是我的动作
But my movement...
如此缓慢
was so slow...
令人难以察觉
that it's imperceptible.
不是
Mmm, no.
我坚信没人能看到我
I'm sure I'm invisible.
德拉克斯
Hi, Drax.
该死的
Damn it.
虚  无  知  地
这地方似乎已经荒废了
This place looks deserted.
第三象限有动静
I'm reading movement in the third quadrant.
没错  我也看到了
Yep, I'm picking that up too.
我们在这里降落吧
Let's put down right here.
东西不在我这里
I don't have it.
银河系的人都知道
Everyone in the galaxy knows
你愿出卖亲兄弟
you'd sell your own brother...
来为你可悲的收藏
if you thought it would add even the slightest trinket
增添一点小装饰品
to your pathetic collection.
我知道现实宝石在你手上  蒂万
I know you have the Reality Stone, Tivan.
把宝石交给我  你就不必遭受折磨
Giving it to me will spare you a great deal of suffering.
我和你说了
I told you.
我卖掉了
I sold it.
我为什么要骗你
Why would I lie?
我想骗人是你的天性
I imagine it's like breathing for you.
那是自杀
Like suicide.
看来你明白啊
You do understand.
就算是你也不会交出如此宝贵的东西
Not even you would surrender something so precious.
我当时并不知道它是什么
I didn't know what it was.
那你比我想的还蠢
Then you're more of a fool than I took you for.
是他
It's him.
最后的机会  你这骗子
Last chance, charlatan.
宝石呢
Where's the stone?
今天
Today...
德拉克斯
Drax. Drax.
他要为我妻女的死付出代价
...he pays for the deaths of my wife and daughter.
德拉克斯  等等
Drax, wait.
别急  别急
Not yet, not yet, not yet.
德拉克斯
Drax.
德拉克斯  听我说
Drax, Drax, Drax. Listen to me.
他还没拿到宝石
He doesn't have the stone yet.
如果我们拿到宝石  就能阻止他
If we get it, then we can stop him.
我们得先拿到宝石  没错
We have to get the stone first. Yeah.
不
No.
不  为了奥薇特  为了卡玛莉亚
No. For Ovette, for Camaria.
睡吧
Sleep.
好吧
Okay.
卡魔拉  螳螂  你们去右边
Gamora, Mantis, you go right.
另一个右边
The other right.
为什么
Why?
为什么是你  女儿
Why you, daughter?
好快啊
That was quick.
了不起  了不起  了不起
Magnificent! Magnificent! Magnificent!
你难过了吗  女儿
Is that sadness I sense in you, daughter?
我心里知道  你依然在乎我
In my heart, I knew you still cared.
但毕竟没法确定
But one never knows for sure.
现实往往令人失望
Reality is often disappointing.
至少以前是的
That is, it was.
现在
Now...
现实可以任我摆布了
reality can be whatever I want.
你早知道我会来
You knew I'd come.
我就指望着呢
I counted on it.
我们需要谈谈  小家伙
There's something we need to discuss, little one.
灭霸
Thanos!
不
No!
放了她  奶昔大哥
Let her go, Grimace.
彼得
Peter.
我叫你走右边的
I told you to go right.
现在还说这个
Now? Really?
你放了她
You let her go!
你是那个男友
Ah, the boyfriend.
不
No.
我更喜欢自视为
Like to think of myself more as a
杀泰坦的长期炮友
Titan-killing, long-term booty call.
-放了她  -彼得
- Let her go. - Peter.
否则我轰掉你阴囊一样的下巴
I'm gonna blow that nutsack of a chin right off your face.
不是他
Not him.
你答应过我  你答应了
You promised. You promised.
女儿
Oh, daughter.
你对他提的要求他做不到
You expect too much from him.
她跟你提过了  是吧
She's asked, hasn't she?
动手吧
Do it.
动手
Do it!
我叫你走右边的
I told you to go right.
我爱你超过一切
I love you more than anything.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我喜欢他
I like him.
幻视还没消息吗
Still no word from Vision?
卫星在爱丁堡附近跟丢了他
Satellites lost him somewhere over Edinburgh.
驾驶盗走的昆式战斗机
On a stolen Quinjet
还有四个全球头号通缉犯
with four of the world's most wanted criminals.
你知道他们是"罪犯"
You know they're only criminals
只是因为你非要那么称呼他们
because you've chosen to call them that, right, sir?
天呐  罗德
My God, Rhodes.
你鬼扯的本事能跟我有一拼了
Your talent for horseshit rivals my own.
要不是因为《协议》
If it weren't for those Accords,
幻视根本不会走
Vision would've been right here.
我记得你也签了那份文件  中校
I remember your signature on those papers, Colonel.
是啊
That's right.
我也为此付出了代价
And I'm pretty sure I paid for that.
你后悔了吗
You have second thoughts?
现在没了
Not anymore.
国务卿先生
Mr. Secretary.
你好大胆
You got some nerve.
这我承认
I'll give you that.
你现在正需要点胆呢
You could use some of that right now.
世界有危险了
The world's on fire.
你觉得一切都被原谅了吗
And you think all is forgiven?
我想要的不是原谅
I'm not looking for forgiveness.
我更不想征求同意了
And I'm way past asking permission.
地球刚失去了最好的守卫者
Earth just lost her best defender.
我们是来战斗的
So we're here to fight.
如果你想挡路
And if you wanna stand in our way...
我们连你一起打
we'll fight you too.
逮捕他们
Arrest them.
这就去
All over it.
得上军事法庭了
That's a court-martial.
见到你真高兴  队长
It's great to see you, Cap.
你也是  罗德
You too, Rhodey.
你们
You guys...
看上去状况真差
really look like crap.
这几年很辛苦吧
Must've been a rough couple years.
是啊  没怎么住五星酒店
Yeah, well, the hotels weren't exactly five star.
我觉得你们看上去很棒
I think you look great.
是啊  我回来了
Yeah, I'm back.
你好啊  布鲁斯
Hi, Bruce.
小娜
Nat.
好尴尬
This is awkward.
那他们还会再回来吧
So we gotta assume they're coming back, right?
他们显然能找到我们
And they can clearly find us.
我们得全体出动  克林特呢
We need all hands on deck. Where's Clint?
《协议》的事后
After the whole Accords situation,
他和斯科特做了协议
he and Scott took a deal.
他们的家人承受不了  所以他们被软禁在家了
It was too tough on their families. They're on house arrest.
-斯科特是谁  -蚁人
- Who's Scott? - Ant-Man.
有蚁人还有蜘蛛侠
There's an Ant-Man and a Spider-Man?
好吧
Okay, look.
灭霸有全宇宙最大的军队
Thanos has the biggest army in the universe...
他不会罢休的  除非他得到
and he is not gonna stop until he gets...
幻视的宝石
Vision's stone.
那我们得保护它
Then we have to protect it.
不  我们得毁掉它
No, we have to destroy it.
我好好想过了
I've been giving a good deal of thought
我脑袋上的这东西
to this entity in my head.
关于它的性质
About its nature.
以及它的组成
But also its composition.
我觉得如果它遭遇
I think if it were exposed
足够强大的能量源
to a sufficiently powerful energy source...
特性类似其本身的能量  那或许
something very similar to its own signature, perhaps...
它的分子完整性就会被破坏
its molecular integrity could fail.
你也会随之被摧毁
Yeah, and you with it.
这不是个选择
We're not having this conversation.
只有销毁宝石
Eliminating the stone is the only way
才能确保灭霸拿不到它
to be certain that Thanos can't get it.
那代价太高了
That's too high a price.
只有你有能力付出这代价
Only you have the power to pay it.
灭霸威胁宇宙一半的生命
Thanos threatens half the universe.
不能让一人的生命阻碍战胜他的希望
One life cannot stand in the way of defeating him.
这样不对
But it should.
我们不以命换命  幻视
We don't trade lives, Vision.
队长  70年前  你付出生命
Captain, 70 years ago, you laid down your life...
来挽救了多少人
to save how many millions of people?
告诉我  这有什么不同
Tell me, why is this any different?
因为  你可能还有选择
Because you might have a choice.
你的心灵是由
Your mind is made up
许多东西叠加而成的
of a complex construct of overlays.
贾维斯  奥创  托尼  我  宝石
Jarvis, Ultron, Tony, me, the stone.
他们混在了一起
All of them mixed together,
彼此学习
all of them learning from one another.
你是说幻视并不只是那块宝石
You're saying Vision isn't just the stone?
我是说  如果我们取出宝石
I'm saying that if we take out the stone...
还剩下不少的幻视
there's still a whole lot of Vision left.
或许还是最好的部分
Perhaps the best parts.
这能做到吗
Can we do that?
我在这里是不行
Not me, not here.
那你最好赶紧找到
Well, you better find someone
合适的地方和人
and somewhere fast.
罗斯可不会让你们
Ross isn't just gonna let you guys
再回老房间住
have your old rooms back.
我知道个地方
I know somewhere.
瓦  坎  达
御林护卫
The Kingsguard
和女子皇家护卫队都已得到通知
and the Dora Milaje have been alerted.
边境部落呢
And the Border Tribe?
还剩的都通知了
Those that are left.
派人传话去贾巴里
Send word to the Jabari as well.
姆巴库就喜欢好好打一场
M'Baku likes a good fight.
他呢
And what of this one?
他可能已经厌倦了战争
This one may be tired of war.
但白狼已经休息够久了
But the White Wolf has rested long enough.
哪里要打仗了
Where's the fight?
他们就来
On its way.
我为灭霸效力这么久
In all the time I've served Thanos...
从未让他失望过
I have never failed him.
如果我赶到了我们泰坦星的汇合点
If I were to reach our rendezvous on Titan...
而时间宝石还连在
with the Time Stone still attached
你这讨厌鬼身上
to your vaguely irritating person...
我会受到  责罚的
there would be judgment.
给我
Give me...
宝石
the stone.
你还真是件忠心耿耿的外套啊
You're a seriously loyal piece of outerwear, aren't you?
说到忠诚
Yeah, uh, speaking of loyalty...
什么...
What the...
-我知道你要说什么  -你不该在这儿的
- I know what you're gonna say. - You should not be here.
-我本想回家的  -我不想听
- I was gonna go home. - I don't wanna hear it.
但下去的路好远啊
But it was such a long way down
我路上就在想你
and I just thought about you on the way...
你还说上了
And now I gotta hear it.
然后我就卡在飞船边上了
...and kinda stuck to the side of the ship.
这件战衣的直觉特别准
And this suit is ridiculously intuitive,
-真的  -该死
- by the way. - God damn it.
所以如果要说  我在这儿其实怪你
So, if anything, it's kinda your fault that I'm here.
-你说什么  -我收回
- What did you just say? - I take that back.
现在  我在外太空里了
And now, I'm here in space.
是啊  在我不想要你在的地方
Yeah, right where I didn't want you to be.
这里不是科尼岛  不是学校出游
This isn't Coney Island. This isn't a field trip.
这可是有去无回
This is a one-way ticket.
听到了吗  别假装你都想清楚了
You hear me? Don't pretend you thought this through.
-不  我想清楚了  -你肯定没有
- No, I did think this through. - I know you didn't.
你根本不可能想清楚了
You could not have possibly thought this through.
我想当个友好邻居蜘蛛侠
You can't be a friendly neighborhood Spider-Man...
但没有邻居了还怎么做
if there's no neighborhood.
好吧  这话不是很通
Okay, that didn't really make sense,
但你明白我想说什么
but you know what I'm trying to say.
好了  还有情况要处理呢
Come on. We got a situation.
看到下面那个了吗  他有麻烦了
See him down there? He's in trouble.
你有什么计划
What's your plan?
说吧
Go.
好吧
Okay, okay...
好吧  你看过一部特老的电影《异形》吗
Okay. Did you ever see this really old movie, Aliens?
疼吧  是不是
Painful, aren't they?
原本是用来做显微手术的
They were originally designed for microsurgery.
任何一个
And any one of them...
都能瞬间杀死你的朋友
could end your friend's life in an instant.
我得告诉你  他算不上是我的朋友
I gotta tell you, he's not really my friend.
救他命更多是职业上的礼貌
Saving his life is more of a professional courtesy.
你什么都没救
You've saved nothing.
你的力量跟我比微不足道
Your powers are inconsequential compared to mine.
是啊  但那孩子看的电影多
Yeah, but the kid's seen more movies.
棒啊  等等  这是什么
Yes! Wait. What are those?
我们还没正式介绍过呢
Hey, we haven't officially met.
好吧
Cool.
我们得调头回去
We gotta turn this ship around.
是啊  他现在想跑了
Yeah, now he wants to run.
-好计划  -我想保护宝石
- Great plan. - No, I want to protect the stone.
我还想要你谢我呢
And I want you to thank me.
说吧  我听着呢
Now, go ahead. I'm listening.
谢什么  差点把我轰进太空里吗
For what? Nearly blasting me into space?
刚是谁救了你个魔法师  是我
Who just saved your magical ass? Me.
真不知道你这么膨胀的脑袋怎么塞得进头盔里
I seriously don't know how you fit your head into that helmet.
承认吧  你早该听我的躲起来
Admit it, you should've ducked out when I told you to.
我让你别插手的  你不肯
I tried to bench you. You refused.
不像你人生中的其他所有人  我不为你工作
Unlike everyone else in your life, I don't work for you.
因为这个
And due to that fact,
我们现在在一艘飞行甜甜圈上
we're now in a flying doughnut...
离地球十万八千里  还没有后援
billions of miles from Earth with no backup.
-我是后援  -不  你是偷渡的
- I'm backup. - No, you're a stowaway.
大人说话呢
The adults are talking.
抱歉  我搞不懂你们什么关系
I'm sorry, I'm confused as to the relationship here.
他是你的养子吗
What is he, your ward?
不是
No.
-我是彼得  -斯特兰奇博士[奇异博士]
- I'm Peter, by the way. - Doctor Strange.
你在用诨号吗
You're using our made-up names.
那我是蜘蛛侠
I'm Spider-Man, then.
这艘船在自我纠正航线
This ship is self-correcting its course.
它在自动驾驶
Thing's on autopilot.
我们能控制它吗
Can we control it?
飞回家
Fly us home?
-斯塔克  -嗯
- Stark? - Yeah.
你能带我们回家吗
Can you get us home?
我听到了
Yeah, I heard you.
我在想  或许我们不该回去
I'm thinking I'm not so sure we should.
我们决不能
Under no circumstances
把时间宝石送去灭霸那里
can we bring the Time Stone to Thanos.
你恐怕还不明白
I don't think you quite understand
-事情的严重性吧  -什么  不
- what's at stake here. - What? No.
是你不明白
It's you who doesn't understand...
灭霸萦绕我的脑海六年了
that Thanos has been inside my head for six years.
自从他派了支军队去纽约
Since he sent an army to New York
现在他又回来了
and now he's back.
我不知道该怎么办
And I don't know what to do.
所以我不能确定
So I'm not so sure
是该在我们的地盘还是他的地盘跟他打
if it's a better plan to fight him on our turf or his...
但你看到了他们做的事  看到了他们能做什么
but you saw what they did, what they can do.
至少去他的地盘  还能出其不意
At least on his turf, he's not expecting it.
我说  我们打上门去
So I say we take the fight to him.
博士
Doctor.
你同意吗
Do you concur?
好吧  斯塔克  我们去找他
All right, Stark. We go to him.
但你要明白
But you have to understand...
如果我要选择救你
if it comes to saving you
那孩子  或是时间宝石
or the kid or the Time Stone...
我会毫不犹豫地任你们死去
I will not hesitate to let either of you die.
我必须如此  因为这事关宇宙的命运
I can't, because the universe depends on it.
好  好三观
Nice. Good, moral compass.
我们没问题了
We're straight.
好吧  小子
All right, kid.
你是复仇者了
You're an Avenger now.
我觉得你可能饿了
I thought you might be hungry.
我一直讨厌那椅子
I always hated that chair.
我听说了
So I've been told.
即便如此  我还是希望有天你能坐上去
Even so, I'd hoped you'd sit in it one day.
我讨厌这个房间
I hated this room.
这艘飞船
This ship.
我讨厌我曾经的生活
I hated my life.
这你也跟我说过
You told me that too.
每天都说
Every day.
说了将近20年
For almost 20 years.
你带走我时  我还是孩子
I was a child when you took me.
我救了你
I saved you.
不
No.
不  我们在母星上时  本来很幸福
No. We were happy on my home planet.
饿着肚子睡觉
Going to bed hungry...
到处找残羹冷炙
scrounging for scraps.
你的星球当时已濒临崩溃
Your planet was on the brink of collapse.
是我阻止了那发生
I'm the one who stopped that.
你知道它后来怎么样了吗
Do you know what's happened since then?
新生的孩子
The children born...
都能吃饱肚子  看到清澈的天空
have known nothing but full bellies and clear skies.
那里成了天堂
It's a paradise.
因为你杀了半个星球的人
Because you murdered half the planet.
为得到拯救  这只是小小代价
A small price to pay for salvation.
你疯了
You're insane.
小家伙  这只是简单的数学
Little one, it's a simple calculus.
宇宙是有限的  资源也是有限的
This universe is finite, its resources finite.
如果生命不加以控制  就会消亡
If life is left unchecked, life will cease to exist.
它需要纠正
It needs correction.
这你怎么知道
You don't know that!
只有我知道这个道理
I'm the only one who knows that.
至少  只有我愿意为此采取行动
At least, I'm the only one with the will to act on it.
曾经
For a time...
你也有那样的意愿
you had that same will...
与我一同战斗
as you fought by my side.
女儿
Daughter.
我不是你的女儿
I'm not your daughter.
我恨自己的一切都是你教的
Everything I hate about myself you taught me.
而你因此
And, in doing so,
也成了银河系里最威猛的女人
made you the fiercest woman in the galaxy.
所以我派你去寻找灵魂宝石
That's why I trusted you to find the Soul Stone.
抱歉我让你失望了
I'm sorry I disappointed you.
我是失望
I am disappointed.
但不是因为你没找到
But not because you didn't find it.
是因为你找到了
But because you did.
但你却撒谎了
And you lied.
星云
Nebula.
别这样
Don't do this.
一段时间之前
Some time ago,
你妹妹溜上船来杀我
your sister snuck aboard this ship to kill me.
求你别这样
Please don't do this.
还差点成功了
And very nearly succeeded.
所以我把她带来了这里
So I brought her here.
好跟她谈谈
To talk.
住手  住手
Stop. Stop it.
我以生命起誓
I swear to you on my life.
我没找到灵魂宝石
I never found the Soul Stone.
读取记忆文件
Accessing memory files.
你知道他要做什么
You know what he's about to do.
他总算准备好了  他要去找宝石
He's finally ready, and he's going for the stones.
-所有宝石  -他不可能得到所有宝石
- All of them. - He can never get them all.
他会的
He will!
他不能  星云
He can't, Nebula.
因为我找到了灵魂宝石的地图
Because I found the map to the Soul Stone...
然后把它烧成了灰  我把它烧了
and I burned it to ash. I burned it.
你很强壮
You're strong.
这是我教的
Me.
你很慷慨
You're generous.
这是我教的
Me.
但我可没教过你撒谎
But I never taught you to lie.
所以你很不擅长
That's why you're so bad at it.
灵魂宝石在哪
Where is the Soul Stone?
沃密尔星球
Vormir!
宝石在沃密尔
The stone is on Vormir.
带我去
Show me.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
在杯子里尿
Tinkle in the cup.
我们不看  有什么可看的
We're not looking. What's there to see?
小树枝是什么  谁都见过小树枝
What's a twig? Everybody's seen a twig before.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
树人  把杯子里的东西
Tree, pour what's in the cup
倒进太空里  然后再用杯子
out into space and go in the cup again.
你会格鲁特语
You speak Groot?
阿斯加德教这个  选修课
Yes, they taught it on Asgard. It was an elective.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
等我们快到了你会知道的
You'll know when we're close.
尼德威阿尔的锻炉汲取
Nidavellir's forge harnesses
一颗中子星的炙热能量
the blazing power of a neutron star.
我的锤子就是在那里铸造的
It's the birthplace of my hammer.
可赞了
It's truly awesome.
好吧  该拿出船长的样子了
Okay, time to be the captain.
弟弟死了啊
So, dead brother, huh?
嗯  那是挺烦人的
Yeah, that could be annoying.
他以前也死过
Well, he's been dead before.
但这次可能是真的了
But, no, this time I think it really might be true.
你说你还有姐姐和爸爸
And you said your sister and your dad?
都死了
Both dead.
还有妈妈吧
But still got a mom, though?
被黑暗精灵杀了
Killed by a dark elf.
最好朋友呢
A best friend?
利刃穿心而死
Stabbed through the heart.
你真想执行这趟杀人任务吗
You sure you're up to this particular murder mission?
非常想
Absolutely.
愤怒  复仇  怒火  失去  后悔
Rage and vengeance, anger, loss, regret...
都是很好的动力
they're all tremendous motivators.
让人脑袋很清醒
They really clear the mind.
我没问题的
So I'm good to go.
是啊  但这个灭霸
Yeah, but this Thanos we're talkin' about...
他可是最厉害的
he's the toughest there is.
-他是没打过我  -他打过的
- Well, he's never fought me. - Yeah, he has.
他没打过我两次
He's never fought me twice.
别忘了  我还要去铸把新锤子
And I'm getting a new hammer, don't forget.
这锤子最好厉害
It better be some hammer.
我1500岁了
You know, I'm 1,500 years old.
我杀过的敌人是我岁数的一倍
I've killed twice as many enemies as that.
他们每个人都想杀死我
And every one of them would've rather killed me,
但没人成功过
but none succeeded.
我还活着是因为命运希望我活着
I'm only alive because fate wants me alive.
灭霸只是又一个这样的混蛋
Thanos is just the latest in a long line of bastards...
而他会是又一个我复仇的对象
and he'll be the latest to feel my vengeance.
这是命运的意愿
Fate wills it so.
如果你错了呢
And what if you're wrong?
如果我错了
If I'm wrong, then...
那我还有什么可失去的呢
what more could I lose?
我可以失去很多
I could lose a lot.
我个人而言可以失去很多呢
Me, personally, I could lose a lot.
好吧
Okay.
如果命运真希望你杀了那混球
If fate does want you to kill that crapsack...
你会需要不止一颗眼球
you're gonna need more than one stupid eyeball.
-这是什么  -你说呢
- What's this? - What's it look like?
康特西亚星球上一个混蛋打赌输给我的
Some jerk lost a bet with me on Contraxia.
他把眼睛给你了
He gave you his eye?
不  他给了我100信用点
No, he gave me 100 credits.
我那晚稍后溜进了他房里偷走了他的眼睛
I snuck into his room later that night and stole his eye.
谢谢  好兔子
Thank you, sweet rabbit.
你该洗洗的
I would've washed that.
我唯一能把它从康特西亚偷出来的办法就是塞进我
The only way I could sneak it off Contraxia was up my...
我们到了
Hey, we're here!
这玩意好像不好使
I don't think this thing works.
怎么暗乎乎的
Everything seems dark.
不是眼睛的问题
It ain't the eye.
情况不对
Something's wrong.
中子星熄灭了
The star's gone out.
环也冻住了
And the rings are frozen.
尼  德  威  阿  尔
希望这些矮人
I hope these dwarves
铸造的本事比打扫强
are better at forging than they are cleaning.
或许他们是意识到
Maybe they realized that
自己住在太空里的一个垃圾堆里
they live in a junk pile in the middle of space.
这个锻炉几世纪都没熄过火了
This forge hasn't gone dark in centuries.
你说灭霸有个手套  是吧
You said Thanos had a gauntlet, right?
对  怎么
Yes, why?
像那样的吗
It look anything like that?
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
回飞行舱去
Go back to the pod.
伊特里  等等
Eitri, wait!
住手
Stop!
Stop.
托尔
Thor?
这里发生了什么
What happened here?
你本该保护我们的
You were supposed to protect us.
阿斯加德本该保护我们的
Asgard was supposed to protect us.
阿斯加德被毁了
Asgard is destroyed.
伊特里  手套  你做了什么
Eitri, the glove. What did you do?
环上住了300个矮人
300 dwarves lived on this ring.
我以为如果我听从他的命令  他们就会安全
I thought if I did what he asked, they'd be safe.
我造出了他要的东西
I made what he wanted.
一件能汲取宝石力量的装置
A device capable of harnessing the power of the stones.
然后他还是杀了所有人
Then he killed everyone anyway.
除了我
All except me.
"你的命属于你"  他说
"Your life is yours," He said.
"但你的手  属于我"
"But your hands are mine alone."
伊特里  你的手不是重点
Eitri, this isn't about your hands.
你设计的每一件武器
Every weapon you've ever designed,
每把斧子  锤子  剑
every axe, hammer, sword...
都在你脑袋里
it's all inside your head.
我知道你现在觉得希望尽失
Now, I know it feels like all hope is lost.
相信我  我知道
Trust me, I know.
但你我联手  我们能杀了灭霸
But together, you and I, we can kill Thanos.
螳螂  听好了
Mantis, listen very carefully.
我需要你去泰坦星见我
I need you to meet me on Titan.
怎么了
Hey, what's going on?
我们好像到了
I think we're here.
这玩意恐怕没有自动停车功能
I don't think this rig has a self-park function.
把手伸到方向装置里
Get your hand inside the steering gimbal.
把这个合上
Close those around it.
-懂吗  -好的
- You understand? - Yep, got it.
这是给一个大块头准备的
This was meant for one big guy,
-我们动作得同步  -好的  好了
- so we gotta move at the same time. - Okay, okay. Ready.
我们最好转向
We might wanna turn.
转向  转向啊
Turn! Turn! Turn!
泰  坦  星
你没事吧
You all right?
好悬啊
That was close.
我欠你的
I owe you one.
我想说  如果外星人
Let me just say, if aliens
在我胸腔里植入了卵什么的
wind up implanting eggs in my chest or something...
而我吃掉了你们谁  那我很抱歉
and I eat one of you, I'm sorry.
余下的时间里不许你
I do not want another single pop culture reference
再提流行文化梗了  懂吗
out of you for the rest of the trip. You understand?
我是想说  有东西过来了
I'm trying to say that something is coming.
灭霸
Thanos!
拜托别把你的卵放进我身体里
Please don't put your eggs in me!
别动  小丑
Stay down, clown.
死吧  死亡毯子
Die, blanket of death!
都别动  都给我冷静
Everybody stay where you are. Chill the eff out.
我就问你一次
I'm gonna ask you this one time.
卡魔拉呢
Where is Gamora?
我问你个更好的  卡魔拉是谁
Yeah. I'll do you one better. Who's Gamora?
我问你个更好的  为什么卡魔拉
I'll do you one better. Why is Gamora?
告诉我她在哪  否则我发誓
Tell me where the girl is or I swear to you
我会把这小怪物烧焦的
I'm gonna French fry this little freak.
来吧  你打我的人  我打你的人  来吧
Let's do it. You shoot my guy and I'll blast him. Let's go!
动手吧  奎尔  我承受得住
Do it, Quill! I can take it.
不  他承受不住
No, he can't take it!
她说得对  你承受不住
She's right. You can't.
是吗  你不告诉我她在哪吗  好啊
Oh, yeah? You don't wanna tell me where she is? That's fine.
我杀了你们三个
I'll kill all three of you
然后揍到灭霸开口
and I'll beat it out of Thanos myself.
从你开始
Starting with you.
等等  灭霸
Wait, what, Thanos?
好吧  我问你个问题
All right, let me ask you this one time.
你效忠哪位主人
What master do you serve?
我效忠哪位主人
What master do I serve?
怎么  我该说"耶稣"吗
What am I supposed to say, "Jesus"?
你是地球人
You're from Earth.
我不是地球人  我是密苏里人
I'm not from Earth, I'm from Missouri.
那就是地球  白痴
Yeah, that's on Earth, dipshit.
你打我们干什么
What are you hassling us for?
你们不是灭霸的人
So you're not with Thanos?
灭霸的人
With Thanos?
不  我是来杀灭霸的
No, I'm here to kill Thanos.
他带走了我女人  等等  你们是谁
He took my girl. Wait, who are you?
我们是复仇者  哥们
We're the Avengers, man.
你们是托尔说的人
You're the ones Thor told us about.
你们认识托尔
You know Thor?
是啊
Yeah.
高个  长得不咋样  还需要别人救
Tall guy, not that good-looking, needed saving.
他现在在哪
Where is he now?
这就是你的计划  用砖头拍他
This is the plan? We're gonna hit him with a brick?
这是模具
It's a mold.
国王的武器
A king's weapon.
本该是阿斯加德最强大的
Meant to be the greatest in Asgard.
理论上  它甚至能召唤彩虹桥
In theory, it could even summon the Bifrost.
它有名字吗
Did it have a name?
风暴斧
Stormbreaker.
有点过了
That's a bit much.
要怎么打造它
So how do we make it?
你得重启锻炉
You'll have to restart the forge.
唤醒濒死恒星的核心
Awaken the heart of a dying star.
兔子  启动飞行舱
Rabbit, fire up the pod.
这星球遭遇了什么
The hell happened to this planet?
偏离自转轴八度
It's eight degrees off its axis.
引力到处都是
Gravitational pull is all over the place.
我们有一个优势  他会自己来
Yeah, we got one advantage. He's coming to us.
我们要利用这一点
We'll use it.
好了  我有个计划
All right, I have a plan.
至少有个大致轮廓
Or at least the beginnings of one.
非常简单  我们引他过来
It's pretty simple. We draw him in,
把他打趴下  拿到需要的东西
pin him down, get what we need.
我可不想跟他纠缠[陪他跳舞]
Definitely don't wanna dance with this guy.
我们只想拿手套
We just want the gauntlet.
你打哈欠
Are you yawning?
我讲解计划的时候你竟然打哈欠
In the middle of this, while I'm breaking it down?
你听见我说的了吗
Did you hear what I said?
你说"我们需要计划"之后我就没在听了
I stopped listening after you said, "We need a plan."
好吧  他沉浸在自己的世界里
Okay, Mr. Clean is on his own page.
他们一般不会"不随机应变"
See, "Not winging it" isn't really what they do.
那他们都会什么
Uh, what exactly is it that they do?
打仇恨  拉群架
Kick names, take ass.
没错
Yeah, that's right.
好了  请各位都过来
All right, just get over here, please.
爵先生  能不能让你的伙伴们围过来
Mr. Lord, can you get your folks to circle up?
别爵先生  叫我星爵就好
"Mr. Lord." Star-Lord is fine.
我们得联合起来
We gotta coalesce.
因为如果我们只凭一腔勇气去面对他
'Cause if all we come at him with is a plucky attitude...
哥们  别说什么一腔勇气
Dude, don't call us plucky.
我们不知道那是什么意思
We don't know what it means.
我们很乐观  我喜欢你的计划
All right, we're optimistic, yes. I like your plan.
只不过它烂透了  让我来做计划
Except it sucks, so let me do the plan...
这样就完美无缺了
and that way it might be really good.
告诉他你斗舞拯救宇宙的事
Tell him about the dance-off to save the universe.
-什么斗舞  -不值一提
- What dance-off? - It's nothing.
就像那部电影《浑身是劲》一样
Like in Footloose, the movie?
就是《浑身是劲》那样
Exactly like Footloose.
它依然是史上最棒的电影吗
Is it still the greatest movie in history?
从来都不是
It never was.
别打岔  好不好
Don't encourage this, all right?
-好  -这位飞侠哥顿
- Okay. - We're getting no help
-帮不上我们什么  -《飞侠哥顿》
- from Flash Gordon here. - Flash Gordon?
那可是在夸我哦
By the way, that's a compliment.
别忘了  我有一半人类血统
Don't forget, I'm half human.
也就是说我有一半的蠢
So that 50% of me that's stupid...
而你是百分百的蠢
that's 100% you.
我真佩服你数学这么好
Your math is blowing my mind.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你的朋友经常那样吗
But does your friend often do that?
斯特兰奇  没事吧
Strange, we all right?
你恢复了  你没事
You're back. You're all right.
你刚刚怎么了
Hey, what was that?
我推进了时间  浏览未来的可能性
I went forward in time to view alternate futures.
看即将到来的一战所有可能出现的结果
To see all the possible outcomes of the coming conflict.
你看到了多少种
How many did you see?
一千四百万六百零五种
14,000,605.
我们赢了几种
How many did we win?
一种
One.
沃  密  尔  星  球
灵魂宝石最好在山上
The stone had better be up there.
不然你妹妹就完了
For your sister's sake.
欢迎  灭霸  阿拉尔斯之子
Welcome, Thanos, son of Alars.
卡魔拉  灭霸之女
Gamora, daughter of Thanos.
你认识我们
You know us?
我被诅咒认识所有来到此地的人
It is my curse to know all who journey here.
灵魂宝石在哪
Where is the Soul Stone?
你应该知道
You should know...
得到它的代价极大
it extracts a terrible price.
我准备好了
I am prepared.
我们一开始都这么以为
We all think that at first.
但我们都错了
We are all wrong.
你怎么如此熟悉这里
How is it you know this place so well?
上一世我也想找无限宝石
A lifetime ago, I, too, sought the stones.
甚至曾把一个攥在手里过
I even held one in my hand.
但它把我流放到这里
But it cast me out, banished me here.
指引别人寻找我无法拥有的珍宝
Guiding others to a treasure I cannot possess.
你所寻找的就在你面前
What you seek lies in front of you.
你所害怕的也在那里
As does what you fear.
这是什么
What's this?
代价
The price.
无限宝石中  灵魂宝石很特别
Soul holds a special place among the Infinity Stones.
可以说它有一定的智慧
You might say it has a certain wisdom.
告诉我它需要什么
Tell me what it needs.
为了确保拥有它的人
To ensure that whoever possesses it...
理解它的力量
understands its power...
灵魂宝石需要献祭
the stone demands a sacrifice.
献祭什么
Of what?
要得到灵魂宝石
In order to take the stone,
你必须失去自己的珍爱之物
you must lose that which you love.
以一个灵魂
A soul...
换取一个灵魂
for a soul.
我这一生  都梦想有一天
All my life, I dreamed of a day...
有一瞬
a moment...
让你得到应有的报应
when you got what you deserved.
而我总是会失望
And I was always so disappointed.
但现在
But now...
你杀戮  折磨
You kill and torture...
还说这是仁慈
and you call it mercy.
宇宙已对你作出了评判
The universe has judged you.
你想得到奖赏  而它拒绝了你
You asked it for a prize, and it told you no.
你失败了
You failed.
知道为什么吗
And do you wanna know why?
因为你没有爱过
Because you love nothing.
你谁也不爱
No one.
不
No.
不是吧
Really?
还流泪
Tears?
他不是为自己流泪
They're not for him.
不
No.
这不是爱
This isn't love.
我曾忽视过自己的命运
I ignored my destiny once.
我不能再重蹈覆辙
I cannot do that again.
就算是为你也不行
Even for you.
对不起了  小家伙
I'm sorry, little one.
不
No!
高度降至2600  030方向
Drop to 2600, heading 0-3-0.
希望你是对的
I hope you're right about this.
否则我们降落的速度会比你希望的快得多
Or we're gonna land a lot faster than you want to.
你说我们要让瓦坎达
When you said we were going to open Wakanda
对世界开放
to the rest of the world...
我没想到是这样
this is not what I imagined.
那你以为是什么样
And what did you imagine?
奥运会
The Olympics.
或许开家星巴克
Maybe even a Starbucks.
我们要鞠躬吗
Should we bow?
要  他是国王
Yeah, he's a king.
我好像总要为什么谢你
Seems like I'm always thanking you for something.
你在干嘛呢
What are you doing?
我们这儿没这习俗
Uh, we don't do that here.
我们会遭到多猛烈的袭击
So how big of an assault should we expect?
先生  我认为你应该准备应对非常猛烈的袭击
Sir, I think you should expect quite a big assault.
情况如何
How we looking?
我的御林护卫会参战
You will have my Kingsguard,
还有边境部落  女子皇家护卫队  还有...
the Border Tribe, the Dora Milaje, and...
一个还算稳定的百岁老人
And a semi-stable 100-year-old man.
你怎么样了  巴基
How you been, Buck?
还行吧  毕竟都快世界末日了
Not bad, for the end of the world.
多态结构的
The structure is polymorphic.
对  神经元是非序列排列的
Right, we had to attach each neuron non-sequentially.
为什么不直接
Why didn't you just
重新编码突触  让它们协调工作
reprogram the synapses to work collectively?
因为我们没想到
Because we didn't think of it.
你相信你尽力了
I'm sure you did your best.
你能做到吗
Can you do it?
可以  但这里有超过两万亿神经元
Yes, but there are more than two trillion neurons here.
一点小误差就可能导致大规模的回路故障
One misalignment could cause a cascade of circuit failures.
会需要点时间  哥哥
It will take time, brother.
多长时间
How long?
越长越好
As long as you can give me.
有东西进入了大气层
Something's entered the atmosphere.
队长  我们有麻烦了
Hey, Cap, we got a situation here.
天哪  我爱这个地方
God, I love this place.
别高兴太早  各位
Yeah, don't start celebrating yet, guys.
穹顶外有更多入侵者过来了
We got more incoming outside the dome.
来不及了
It's too late.
我们现在就得把宝石毁掉
We need to destroy the stone now.
幻视  你给我躺回去
Vision, get your ass back on the table.
我们会拖住它们
We will hold them off.
旺达  这石头一旦从他头部取出
Wanda, as soon as that stone's out of his head...
你就把它毁掉
you blow it to hell.
我会的
I will.
全城疏散  启动全面防御
Evacuate the city. Engage all defenses.
给这人拿块盾牌
And get this man a shield.
我认为你没太搞懂状况
I don't think you get the scientifics here.
这些环很巨大  你想移动它们
These rings are gigantic. You wanna get them moving...
会需要大得多的东西才能把它们带动起来
you're gonna need something a lot bigger to yank 'em loose.
-交给我  -交给你
- Leave that to me. - Leave it to you?
伙计  你在太空里
Buddy, you're in space.
你就拿了一根绳和一个...
All you got is a rope and a...
发动引擎
Fire the engines!
再加把力  兔子
More power, rabbit!
干得漂亮  小子
Well done, boy.
那就是尼德威阿尔
That's Nidavellir.
该死
Damn it.
"该死"  "该死"是什么意思
"Damn it"? What's "Damn it"?
机械装置坏了
The mechanism is crippled.
-什么  -光圈不打开
- What? - With the iris closed,
我就没法加热金属
I can't heat the metal.
加热需要多久
How long will it take to heat it?
几分钟  或许更久  怎么了
A few minutes, maybe more. Why?
我去把它撑开
I'm gonna hold it open.
那是自杀
That's suicide.
不拿风暴斧就去找灭霸也是自杀
So is facing Thanos without that axe.
情况如何  布鲁斯
How we looking, Bruce?
我觉得我已经掌握诀窍了
Yeah, I think I'm getting the hang of it.
感觉太棒了
This is amazing, man.
就像不用变身就成了绿巨人
It's like being the Hulk without actually...
我没事  我没事
I'm okay. I'm okay.
有两处热信号
I've got two heat signatures
要冲破林线了
breaking through the tree line.
谢谢你和我们并肩作战
Thank you for standing with us.
你那个朋友呢
Where's your other friend?
他的命你要用命偿
You will pay for his life with yours.
灭霸会拿到那块宝石的
Thanos will have that stone.
不可能
That's not gonna happen.
你是在瓦坎达
You are in Wakanda now.
灭霸除了灰烬和鲜血什么也别想得到
Thanos will have nothing but dust and blood.
我们...
We
不吝鲜血
have blood to spare.
他们投降了吗
They surrender?
并没有
Not exactly.
什么鬼
What the hell?
看来惹毛她了
Looks like we pissed her off.
他们在自杀
They're killing themselves.
看到他们的牙了吗
You see the teeth on those things?
好了  你退后  山姆
All right, back up, Sam.
别烧了你的翅膀
You're gonna get your wings singed.
队长  如果他们绕过防线
Cap, if these things circle the perimeter
从我们后面进来
and get in behind us...
就没人挡在他们和幻视之间了
there's nothing between them and Vision.
那我们最好确保他们都在我们眼前
Then we better keep 'em in front of us.
怎么做
How do we do that?
打开屏障
We open the barrier.
听我口令  打开西北17区屏障
On my signal, open North-West Section Seventeen.
请求确认  陛下
Requesting confirmation, My King.
你是说要打开屏障吗
You said open the barrier?
听我口令
On my signal.
这将是瓦坎达的末日
This will be the end of Wakanda.
那也是史上最壮烈的末日
Then it will be the noblest ending in history.
瓦坎达万岁
Wakanda forever!
打开
Now!
还需要多久  苏睿
How much longer, Shuri?
我都还没开始  哥哥
I've barely begun, brother.
你最好快点
You might want to pick up the pace.
众神之父  赐我力量
Allfathers, give me strength.
你清楚吗  小子
You understand, boy?
你这是要承受一颗恒星的所有能量
You're about to take the full force of a star.
你会没命的
It'll kill you.
除非我死了
Only if I die.
对
Yes.
没命就是这个意思
That's what killing you means.
撑住  撑住  托尔
Hold it! Hold it, Thor!
托尔  说话  拜托
Thor! Say something. Come on.
托尔  你没事吧
Thor, you okay?
我觉得他要死了
I think he's dying.
他需要风暴斧
He needs the axe!
斧柄呢
Where's the handle?
树人  快帮我找斧柄
Tree, help me find the handle!
太多了
There's too many of 'em!
这下你们倒霉了
You guys are so screwed now!
给我叫灭霸出来
Bring me Thanos!
嗯
Oh, yeah.
你是像个灭霸
You're much more of a Thanos.
看来乌木喉已经死了
I take it the Maw is dead.
今天损失惨重
This day extracts a heavy toll.
不过  他也算完成了任务
Still, he accomplished his mission.
对你恐怕不是好事
You may regret that.
他带你来
He brought you face-to-face
正面迎战魔法师了
with the Master of the Mystic Arts.
那你觉得他把你带来了哪里
And where do you think he brought you?
我猜猜  你家吗
Let me guess. Your home?
曾经是
It was.
而且它曾经美丽
And it was beautiful.
泰坦曾经如同很多行星
Titan was like most planets.
要吃饭的嘴多  能吃的却远远不够
Too many mouths, not enough to go around.
当我们面临灭绝  我提出了解决方案
And when we faced extinction, I offered a solution.
屠杀
Genocide.
但是随机  公正  不分贫富
But random, dispassionate, fair to rich and poor alike.
他们说我疯了
They called me a madman.
我的预言最终成真了
And what I predicted came to pass.
恭喜  你是预言家
Congratulations, you're a prophet.
我是幸存者
I'm a survivor.
想谋杀数十亿生命的幸存者
Who wants to murder trillions.
集齐六颗宝石  只要我一个响指
With all six stones, I could simply snap my fingers.
他们就将灰飞烟灭  我认为这是慈悲
They would all cease to exist. I call that mercy.
然后呢
And then what?
然后是久违的休息
I'd finally rest...
在全宇宙的感激中坐看日出
and watch the sun rise on a grateful universe.
最难的抉择需要最强的意志
The hardest choices require the strongest wills.
你会发现我们的意志不比你弱
I think you'll find our will equal to yours.
我们
Our?
小菜一碟  奎尔
Piece of cake, Quill.
没错  如果你的目标是激怒他  你做到了
Yeah, if your goal was to piss him off.
别让他握拳
Don't let him close his fist.
魔法
Magic.
魔法再来
More magic.
魔法踢
Magic with a kick.
魔法...
Magic with a...
小虫子
Insect!
好啊
Well, well.
你该杀了我的
You should've killed me.
那多浪费零件
It would've been a waste of parts!
卡魔拉呢
Where's Gamora?
晕了吗  别放手
Is he under? Don't let up.
要快  他很强壮
Be quick. He is very strong.
帕克  帮忙  过来
Parker, help! Get over here.
她控制不住多久  开始
She can't hold him much longer. Let's go.
得张开他的手指才能脱下来
We gotta open his fingers to get it off.
我以为他不好抓呢
I thought you'd be hard to catch.
说清楚  这是我的计划
For the record, this was my plan.
现在不怎么威风了吧
You're not so strong now, huh?
卡魔拉呢
Where is Gamora?
我的卡魔拉
My Gamora.
胡扯
No, bullshit!
她在哪
Where is she?
他很痛苦
He is in anguish.
很好
Good.
他在哀悼
He... He mourns.
这个怪物能为什么哀悼
What does this monster have to mourn?
卡魔拉
Gamora.
什么
What?
他带她去了沃密尔星球
He took her to Vormir.
然后带了灵魂宝石回来
He came back with the Soul Stone.
却没有她
But she didn't.
奎尔  你得冷静下来  明白吗
Okay, Quill, you gotta cool it right now. You understand?
别跟他打  我们快拔下来了
Don't, don't. Don't engage. We almost got this off!
告诉我她在撒谎
Tell me she's lying.
混蛋  告诉我你没那么做
Asshole, tell me you didn't do it!
我没办法
I had to.
不  你没有
No, you didn't.
你没有
-你怎么能  -奎尔
- No, you didn't! - Quill!
住手  住手
Hey, stop! Hey, stop! Stop!
住手
Hey, stop! Stop!
下来了  下来了  我抓到了
It's coming, it's coming. I got it, I got it!
天呐
Oh, God.
来吃瘪啊  太空狗
Come and get some, space dogs!
来啊  叫你们好看
Come on! Get some! Get some!
来啊  尝尝我的厉害
Come on! Get some!
-枪怎么卖  -不卖
- How much for the gun? - Not for sale.
好吧  那你胳膊怎么卖
Okay. How much for the arm?
那胳膊我要定了
Oh, I'll get that arm.
新发型
New haircut?
你学我留胡子了
Noticed you've copied my beard.
对了  这是我朋友  树人
By the way, this is a friend of mine, Tree.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
我是史蒂夫·罗杰斯
I am Steve Rogers.
撤退  马上撤退
Fall back! Fall back, now!
集中对左侧开火  山姆
Focus that fire on the left flank, Sam.
我在开火呢
I'm doing it.
她刚刚怎么不来
Why was she up there all this time?
她下来了  去拿吧
She's on the field. Take it.
各位  幻视那边有情况
Guys, we got a Vision situation here.
谁去帮助幻视
Somebody get to Vision!
-我去  -我就去
- I got him! - On my way.
他会孤独一人死去  你也是
He'll die alone. As will you.
她不是一个人
She's not alone.
不  别想
Oh, no, you don't.
这可不会像纽约那样
This isn't gonna be like New York, pal.
这套战甲能把绿巨人扁得求饶
This suit's already kicked the crap outta the Hulk.
什么  别
What? No! No!
各位  幻视需要支援  马上
Guys! Vision needs backup, now!
绿巨人  绿巨人
Hulk? Hulk,
我知道你喜欢最后时刻出场
I know you like making your entrance at the last second.
时候到了  这已经是最后的最后时刻了
Well, this is it, man. This is the last, last second.
绿巨人  绿巨人
Hulk! Hulk!
绿巨人
Hulk!
不
No!
去你的  你个大绿混蛋
Oh, screw you, you big, green asshole!
我自己来
I'll do it myself!
来吧  好啊
Come on! Yeah!
回见
See ya!
绿巨人  我们有很多得谈的  哥们
Hulk, we got a lot to figure out, pal.
我以为你很强大呢  机器
I thought you were formidable, machine.
但你要死了  与常人无异
But you're dying, like any man.
快走
Get outta here!
走啊
Go!
恶心死了
That was really gross.
我不是叫你走吗
I thought I told you to go.
我们不以命换命  队长
We don't trade lives, Captain.
接住你了  接住你了
I got you. I got you.
抱歉我不记得大家的名字
I'm sorry I can't remember anybody's names.
你挺会变戏法  巫师
You're full of tricks, wizard.
但你没用过你最强大的武器
Yet you never once used your greatest weapon.
假的
A fake.
你再拿卫星砸我  我就要失控了
You throw another moon at me, and I'm gonna lose it.
斯塔克
Stark.
你认识我
You know me?
是的
I do.
你不是唯一背负知识诅咒的人
You're not the only one cursed with knowledge.
我唯一的诅咒就是你
My only curse is you.
来啊
Come on!
费这么大事  就让我留了一滴血
All that for a drop of blood.
我尊重你  斯塔克
You have my respect, Stark.
等我完事  还有一半人类能存活下来
When I'm done, half of humanity will still be alive.
希望他们会记得你
I hope they remember you.
住手
Stop.
饶他一命
Spare his life...
我就把宝石给你
and I will give you the stone.
不许耍花招
No tricks.
别
Don't.
还剩一个
One to go.
他在哪
Where is he?
我们刚刚输了吗
Did we just lose?
你为什么要那么做
Why would you do that?
这是终局了
We're in the endgame now.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
什么  怎么了
What? What is it?
他来了
He's here.
各位  到我这里  来敌人了
Everyone, on my position. We have incoming.
怎么回事
What the hell?
队长
Cap.
就是他
That's him.
注意  精神点
Eyes up. Stay sharp.
旺达
Wanda.
是时候了
It's time.
不
No.
他们无法阻止他  旺达  但我们能
They can't stop him, Wanda, but we can.
看着我
Look at me.
你有能力摧毁宝石
You have the power to destroy the stone.
-别  -你必须这么做  旺达  求你
- Don't. - You must do it. Wanda, please.
我们没时间了
We are out of time.
我不能
I can't.
你可以的
Yes, you can.
You can.
如果他拿到宝石  半个宇宙都会死
If he gets the stone, half the universe dies.
这不公平
It's not fair.
不该由你来  但就是这样
It shouldn't be you, but it is.
没事的
It's all right.
你不会伤害我的
You could never hurt me.
我只感觉到你
I just feel you.
没事的
It's all right.
我爱你
I love you.
我理解  孩子
I understand, my child.
比任何人都能理解
Better than anyone.
你才不会懂呢
You could never.
今天  我失去的远超你的想象
Today, I lost more than you can know.
但现在不是哀悼的时候
But now is no time to mourn.
现在  时间不存在了
Now is no time at all.
不
No!
我说过
I told you...
我会要你偿命的
you'd die for that.
你该
You should have...
You should...
你该砍头的
You should have gone for the head.
不
No!
女儿
Daughter?
你做到了吗
Did you do it?
是的
Yes.
代价是什么
What did it cost?
一切
Everything.
你做了什么
What did you do?
What'd you do?
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
托尔
Thor.
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
史蒂夫
Steve?
起来  将军  起来
Up, General. Up!
我们不能死在这里
This is no place to die.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
不不不
No, no, no!
格鲁特  不要
Groot! No.
山姆
Sam!
山姆  你在哪
Sam, where you at?
出事了
Something's happening.
奎尔
Quill?
稳住  奎尔
Steady, Quill.
天呐
Oh, man.
托尼
Tony.
这是唯一的办法
There was no other way.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark?
我感觉不太好
I don't feel so good.
你没事的
You're all right.
我不...知道是怎么回事
I don't... I don't know what's happening.
我不知道
I don't know...
我不想走
I don't want to go.
我不想走  先生  求你
I don't want to go, sir. Please.
求你  我不想走  我不想走
Please, I don't want to go. I don't want to go.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他做到了
He did it.
怎么回事  这是怎么回事
What is this? What the hell is happening?
天呐
Oh, God.
复仇者联盟3：无限战争
斯塔克还没有消息吗
Still no word from Stark?
还没有
No, not yet.
我们在监控两个半球的
We're watching every satellite
每一颗人造卫星  毫无发现
on both hemispheres, but still nothing.
怎么了
What is it?
瓦坎达上空多个不明物体
Multiple bogeys over Wakanda.
跟纽约的能量信号一样吗
Same energy signature as New York?
大10倍
Ten times bigger.
告诉克莱恩我们去...
Tell Klein we'll meet him at...
尼克  尼克
Nick! Nick!
他们没事吧
They okay?
里面没人
There's no one here.
呼叫控制中心
Call Control.
红色警报
Code red.
尼克
Nick.
希尔
Hill.
不
Oh, no.
妈了个...
Mother...
正在发送
灭霸将会回归